Guide to the J. E. Wallace Sterling, President of Stanford University, Papers
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Series 1
  - Japanese Grants-in-Aid, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Japan International Christian University Foundation (ICU), 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Japan International Christian University Foundation (ICU), 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Japan International Christian University Foundation (ICU), 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Organized by Prof. Claude A. Buss, Chairman, Committee for Pacific-East Asian Studies
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Rockefeller Foundation grant of $20,000
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Japan - Seminar on American Studies in Tokyo, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Japan Society of San Francisco, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Sterling was First Vice President and on founding board of directors
  - Japan Society of San Francisco, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Japan Society of San Francisco, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Japan Society of San Francisco, 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Japanese Visitors, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Japanese Visitors, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Jordan, David Starr - 100th Anniversary, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Jordan, Mrs. Jessie Knight, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Wife of David Starr Jordan
  - Jordan, Mrs. Jessie Knight, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - General "L", 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - General "K", 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - General "K", 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - General "K", 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - General "K", 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - General "K", 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - General "K", 1949-1951 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    Kimpton, Lawrence A. - Univ. of Chicago Chancellor Kitching
  - Kaiser Permanente Hospital, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    Bid by Kaiser to affiliate Stanford with a new hospital to be built in San Francisco
  - KQED Formerly Bay Area Educational Television Association, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Krzywoblocki, M. Z., 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - General "L", 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - General "L", 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - General "L", 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - General "L", 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - General "L", 1949-1952 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Laboratories for Fundamental Scientific Research at Stanford, Report on, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Land Development - Stein, Clarence, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Leases and Loans, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Leases and Loans, 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Leases and Loans, 1952-1953 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Leases and Loans, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Leases and Loans, 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Leases and Loans, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Listening Post Group, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    Higher education interest group monitoring federal actions
  - Listening Post Group, 1951-1955 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Luthy, Nydia, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Lybrand, Ross Brothers and Montgomery: Accountants, 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - Lybrand, Ross Brothers and Montgomery: Accountants, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - General "M", 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - General "M", 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - General "M", 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - General "M", 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - General "M", 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - General "M", 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - General "M", 1949-1951 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Personal correspondence, includes letter declining offer to become President of University of Michigan
  - General "Mc", 1949-1951 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Personal correspondence
  - McCutcheon, Thomas, Matthew, Griffiths, Greene - Law firm for Stanford, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - McCutcheon, Thomas, Matthew, Griffiths, Greene - Law firm for Stanford, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - McCutcheon, Thomas, Matthew, Griffiths, Greene - Law firm for Stanford, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - McMullin, Mrs. Dare Stark, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - McMullin, Mrs. Dare Stark, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Malik, Charles, 1959-1961 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Attempt bring Prof. Malik to Stanford to start a Middle Eastern Studies program
  - Mark X - President's Ten Year Report, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    School and Department reports
  - Mark X - President's Ten Year Report, 1958-1960 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Mark X - President's Ten Year Report, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Mark X - President's Ten Year Report, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Mark X - President's Ten Year Report, 1960-1962 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Report was never published?
  - Land Use, Master Plan, 1953-1957 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Land Use, Master Plan, 1953-1959 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Skidmore, Owings, and Merrill - Architects; includes blueprints, photos, maps
  - Memorial Church, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Dismissal of Chaplain Paul C. Johnston
  - Memorial Church, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Memorial Church, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    Visiting preachers
  - Memorial Church, 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    New Chaplain R. M. Minto
  - Memorial Church, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Memorial Church, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Memorial Church, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Menlo School and Junior College, 1936-1945 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    Proposals and studies about acquiring the Menlo School
  - Public Exercises Committee, 1943-1946 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Public Exercises Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Memorial Church, 1958-1964 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    includes sections on Acoustics, Structural Report,
  - Microwave Laboratory, 1949-1950 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Linear accelerator, see also Hansen Laboratories
  - Microwave Laboratory, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    see also Hansen Laboratories
  - Microwave Laboratory, 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Microwave Laboratory, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    see also Hansen Laboratories, Linear accelerator
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    later changed to School of Earth Sciences
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1958-1962 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Mineral Sciences, School of, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Art Gallery and Museum, 1946-1949 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Museum, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    see also Art Gallery and Museum, see also Art and Architecture, Dept. of
  - Museum, 1951-1953 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Museum, 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - General "N", 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - General "N", 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - General "N", 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - General "N", 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - General "N", 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - General "N", 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    includes misfiled item from National Science Foundation (NSF)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1953-1954 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - National Education Association (NEA), 1952 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - National Education Association (NEA), 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - National Education Association (NEA), 1953-1953 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - National Education Association (NEA), 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - National Education Association (NEA), 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - National Fund for Medical Education (NFME), 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - National Fund for Medical Education (NFME), 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - National Fund for Medical Education (NFME), 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - National Fund for Medical Education (NFME), 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - National Fund for Medical Education (NFME), 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Sterling was on Advisory Council; Herbert Hoover was Honorary Chairman
  - National Research Council (NRC), 1952 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - National Planning Association (NPA), 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Sterling was on Technical Assistance in Latin America committee (TALA)
  - National Service Office, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Deals with armed services men studying at Stanford under training contracts
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1951 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1952-1962 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    Name to change to Dept. of Systematic Biology in Fall 1962
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Natural History Museum (Biology Dept.), 1954-1956 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Navy - General, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Navy - General, 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Navy - General, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Navy Electronics Laboratory, Survey of, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Navy - General, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - News and Publications Service, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    formerly Information and Publications
  - News and Publications Service, 1956-1962 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - News and Publications Service - Motion Picture Production Unit, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    see also Film Production Unit and Committe on Radio, TV, and Motion Pictures 1959-1960
  - News and Publications Service - Public Information and Fund-raising, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    Activity around announcement of Project M (Stanford Linear Accelerator)
  - News and Publications Service, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    Clipping survey - counts inches of newspaper coverage for Stanford and other schools in papers in Los Angeles and San Francisco
  - General "O", 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - General "O", 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - General "O", 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - General "O", 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Organic Chemistry Research Laboratory, 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - General "P", 1949-1952 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Art Gallery and Museum - Oriental Art at Stanford, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - General "P", 1951-1952 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - General "P", 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - General "P", 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - General "P", 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Pacific Coast Committee for the Humanities (PCCH), 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    Part of American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), John W. Dodds and Sterling were on this committee together before and after Sterling came to Stanford
  - Palo Alto Chamber of Commerce, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Palo Alto, City of, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Palo Alto Hospital Extension, 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    Stanford Trustees refused to approve extension of hospital (operated by Stanford for the City of Palo Alto) on University land
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Palo Alto Hospital - Clippings, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    clippings need to be photocopied
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    Proposed expansion
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    Proposed exapnsion
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1953-1955 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Palo Alto Hospital - Citizens' Hospital Committee Bond Campaign, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Palo Alto Methodist Church - Speech Notes, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Parents' Day, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Parents' Day, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - Partisan Political Activities, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Pasadena City Schools Board of Education, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Sterling on Schools Survey Committee
  - Patents, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Klystrons, Varian, Sperry Gyroscope
  - Peninsula City Officials, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Personal, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Letters leading up to his inauguration; Includes advice from a friend on "the proper line (on communism) for a university president."
  - Personal, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    "Get Well" letters after apendectomy
  - Personal, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Sterling's letter to Board of Trustees stating philosophy of the president's role in a university, understandings of the state of Stanford, and his terms of employment.
  - Personnel, 1944-1964 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, 1948-1955 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Placement Service (for Stanford students), 1948-1949 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Placement Service (for Stanford students), 1949-1950 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Placement Service (for Stanford students), 1951 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Placement Service (for Stanford students), 1952-1964 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Police Department, 1959-1964 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    has Fire Department also
  - Policies - General, 1953-1954 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Policies - Stanford, 1953-1954 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Policies - Stanford, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Polytechnic Elementary School, Pasadena, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    Sterling resigned from Board of Trustees upon moving to Stanford
  - Athletics and Physical Education, Dept. of, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    President's Football Ticket Courtesy LIst
  - Hoover House, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    President's residence
  - Hoover House, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - President's Office, 1948-1949 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    Secretarial and administrative business within the office
  - President's Office, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - President's Office, 1952-1954 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - President's Office, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - President's Office, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    Budget
  - President's Office, 1949-1960 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1943-1953 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    History and Survey; Donald P. Bean, Director
  - Press, Stanford University, 1948-1949 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1949-1950 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1951-1952 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1952-1953 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    "Your Rugged Constitution" publication
  - Press, Stanford University, 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    "American Ideals Series" seeking funding from Coe Foundation
  - Press, Stanford University, 1955-1957 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1955-1956 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    Leon E. Seltzer replaces Donald Bean as Director
  - Press, Stanford University, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    "Stanford University - 1916-1941" by J. Pearce Mitchell
  - Press, Stanford University, 1959-1964 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Press, Stanford University, 1961-1962 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    Efforts to kill or alter "The Mooney Case" by Richard Frost, a book about 1916 Preparedness Day bombings in San Francisco from a class conflict point of view.
  - Promotion, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Promotion, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    Sterling's trip to New York
  - Provost's Office, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Contains letter from Sterling about staffing the Kyoto program
  - Public Relations, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    Fred Glover's speech to elementary school principals on PR, includes a few gag items (poster on becoming a Stanford woman in the quad under a full moon)
  - Quarry - Study of restoring areas in the foothills, 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Questionnaires, 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Questionnaires, 1952-1953 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Questionnaires, 1954-1956 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - General "R", 1948-1949 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - General "R", 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - General "R", 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - General "R", 1952-1953 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - General "R", 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - General "R", 1954-1955 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - General "R", 1956 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Rams Head, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Random House, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Negotiations to publish book about Stanford by Bruce Bliven
  - Random House, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Termination of agreement to publish Stanford book
  - Records Bureau, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Records Bureau, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Harvey Hall, Registrar
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1957-1958 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1953-1955 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Registrar, Office of the, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    Room scheduling
  - Residences and Dining Halls, 1955-1960 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Residences and Dining Halls, 1955-1960 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    Occupancy reports
  - Residences and Dining Halls, 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Restudy of the Needs of Higher Education, State of California's, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Retirement, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Retirement-Non-Academic, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Retirement-Non-Academic, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Reynolds, Ralph (Jim), 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    Letters to the president about Stanford football and communism on campus
  - Reynolds, Ralph (Jim), 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Reynolds, Ralph (Jim), 1950-1972 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Riding Stables, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - General, 1942-1949 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    Contains summary of Rockefeller grants to Stanford 1942-1947
  - General "S", 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - General "S", 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - General "S", 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - General "S", 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - General "S", 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - General "S", 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - General "S", 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Safety Engineer, 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - St. Dennis Martin Cemetery, 1950-1952 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Relocation of cemetery that was on Stanford land
  - Salaries at Other Institutions, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Salaries, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Schedules, University Calendar, 1946-1953 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Secondary Schools (High Schools), 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Secondary Schools (High Schools), 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Schwartz, Dr. Leonard, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    Retirement from Romanic Languages Dept. due to illness
  - Scripps Metabolic Clinic, 1950-1951 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    Bid to associate with Stanford Medical Center
  - Secretarial Training Program, 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Security Clearances, Classified Research, 1952-1954 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Shakespeare Festival, 1962-1964 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Committee for Research in Social Sciences (CRISS), 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    Serra House, Ernest R. Hilgard, Alfred de Grazia
  - Committee for Research in Social Sciences (CRISS), 1953 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Social Security, 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Southern California Office, 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    Donald T. Carlson, Director
  - Southern California Office, 1956-1957 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Southern California Office, 1957-1958 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Southern California Office, 1958-1959 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    Joseph Ruetz, Associate General Secretary
  - Southern Pacific Company, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Southern Pacific Company, 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Speakers Service, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    Survey of programs at other universities
  - Speech and Hearing Clinic, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Spragens, Thomas A. - Assistant to the President, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - President's Office - Staff Calendars, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - President's Office - Staff Calendars, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Staff - General, 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Staff Memos, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Stanford, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Stanford Associates, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Stanford Associates, 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Associates, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Stanford Associates, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    Minutes
  - Stanford Associates, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Stanford Associates, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Stanford Associates, 1955-1956 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Stanford Athletic Board, 1949-1952 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Formerly Stanford Athletic Council
  - Stanford Athletic Board, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Athletic Board, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Athletic Board, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Athletic Board, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Block S Society, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Buck Club, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Buck Club, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Buck Club, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Buck Club, 1955-1956 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Community Rehabilitation Institute, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Convalescent Home, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Convalescent Home, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Council, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Council, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Crew, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Crew, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    Clippings
  - Stanford Daily, 1948-1949 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Daily, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Daily, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Bohemian Club Dinner, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Ram's Head, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Stanford Fund, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Land Development, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Land Development, 1941-1955 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    Board of Trustees resolutions on land planning from 1941-1955
  - Land Development, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Land Development, 1955-1956 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Medical Conference, 1955-1956 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    "To enlist the thinking of experts on the problems of the new Medical School at Stanford."
  - Stanford Mothers of the East Bay, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Mothers' Club of Stanford, 1950-1951 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Mothers' Club of Stanford, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Mothers' Club of Stanford, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 32)